Falmata Dawano

(952) 855-2202 Eden Prairie, MN 55344 Falmata.dawano@gmail.com

Linkedin.com/in/falmata-dawano github.com/falmatad profile.codersrank.io/user/falmatad/

My name is Falmata, a Hardworking Software Engineer, Web Developer, and Web Designer that started his Software Development journey by attending a Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp known as Lambda School, leaving with a solid grasp of web development technologies and agile based development methodologies. As a Software Engineer at Zeefasys, I've had direct experience using various communication and agile methodology tools, owning a product from start to finish, and being a liaison between clients and the engineering team.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Developing RESTful API Consuming Web and Mobile Applications
- Designing Responsive User Interfaces and websites
- Implementation of good UX/UI flow when designing and building Frontend Web Applications
- Evaluating The Most Effective Technologies to Use for Each Web Development Projects
- Following Emerging Trends in Web Development
- Experience Working in an Agile Based Engineering teams to deploy web projects
- Creating Serverless Applications using AWS

TECHNOLOGIES

- Javascript
- React + Redux-Saga/Thunk
- React Native
- NodeJs
- MySQL
- ExpressJs
- HTML5
- CSS3
- CSS PreProcessors
- NPM + Yarn
- Git, GitHub, BitBucket
- AWS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Zeefasys, Eden Prairie, MN

Software Developer April 2020 - Present

- Deploy and manage Websites and Web Applications on AWS
- Use Jira to keep up with Sprint planning and task projections
- Lead the communication between offshore Engineers and clients
- Use Git, Github, and BitBucket for version control
- Create Responsive Modern UI using ReactJs
- Use React Native for cross platform Mobile Development
- Deploy and consume REST APIs using NodeJs and AWS API Gateway
- Build and Manage Databases using MySQL or AWS DynamoDB
- Design and maintain landing pages and websites using HTML5, and CSS

Everyone Should Code LLC, Eden Prairie, MN

Coding Instructor | October 2019 - October 2020

- Worked with Childcare centers and Youth Organizations to teach young coders the fundamentals of computer science
- Develop a custom curriculum for each organization
- Acquire new customers and clients.

Youth Enrichment League, Carver MN

Coding Instructor | October 2018 - May 2019

- Taught and trained Elementary School Age kids the fundamentals of programming
- Developed a customized teaching strategy for each student group
- Developed a fun and interactive app and game projects that were catered to each age group

EDUCATION

Lambda School (Web Development Boot-Camp)

Front-End Web Development Remote/ Agile